[
  {
    "question": "1. Spell the following words: a) Eisteddfod  b) Drunkenness.",
    "answer": "a) Eisteddfod  b) Drunkenness"
  },
  {
    "question": "2. What figure of speech is the phrase “Autumn arrived in his coat of orange, red and gold?”",
    "answer": "Personification"
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Name the author of the book “To Kill A Mockingbird,” who died on February 19th 2016?",
    "answer": "Harper Lee"
  },
  {
    "question": "4. What term is given to a figure of speech in which two successive words seemingly contradict one another as in “wise fool”?",
    "answer": "Oxymoron"
  },
  {
    "question": "5. What word in English is the only word that ends in the letters 'mt'?",
    "answer": "Dreamt"
  },
  {
    "question": "6. What sentence in English uses all the letters of the English alphabet?",
    "answer": "The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog"
  },
  {
    "question": "1. In which city or country would you find The Spanish Steps?",
    "answer": "Rome, Italy"
  },
  {
    "question": "2. What is Turkey’s highest mountain?",
    "answer": "Mount Ararat"
  },
  {
    "question": "3. In which war did Florence Nightingale nurse help the injured?",
    "answer": "Crimean War"
  },
  {
    "question": "4. What are the capital cities of the following countries: a.) Qatar – Doha  b.) Indonesia – Jakarta ?",
    "answer": "Doha (Qatar) and  Jakarta (Indonesia)"
  },
  {
    "question": "5. Which tourist attraction features in Zimbabwe is a result of chemical weathering?",
    "answer": "Chinhoyi Caves"
  },
  {
    "question": "6. Tanzania is a portmanteau name (two word combination) from which two states which united in 1964?",
    "answer": "Tanganyika and Zanzibar"
  },
  {
    "question": "1. The Multinational Joint Task Force is a combined army aimed at destroying Boko Haram in Nigeria, besides Nigeria, name the other two countries involved?",
    "answer": "Chad and Niger"
  },
  {
    "question": "2. List Zimbabwe’s two natural sites listed on World Heritage list?",
    "answer": "Victoria Falls, Mana Pools"
  },
  {
    "question": "3. In which country is the Skeleton Coast National Park found?",
    "answer": "Namibia"
  },
  {
    "question": "4. Name the two languages commonly spoken in Africa, which are not of European origin?",
    "answer": "Arabic and Swahili"
  },
  {
    "question": "5. Name the African city named after a US President, and what was his full name?",
    "answer": "Monrovia, James Monroe"
  },
  {
    "question": "6. Liberated American slaves formed their own country in Africa, name this country?",
    "answer": "Liberia"
  },
  {
    "question": "1. What are numbers 6, 28 and 496 examples of?",
    "answer": "Perfect Numbers (they are equal to sum of all their factors)"
  },
  {
    "question": "2. If, during a mathematical conversion, you multiplied by 5 and divided by 8, what would you be converting?",
    "answer": "Miles to kilometres"
  },
  {
    "question": "3. What do the letters LASER stand for?",
    "answer": "Light Amplification by the Stimulated Emission of Radiation."
  },
  {
    "question": "4. If it takes 5 men to dig 5 holes in 5 hours, how many men does it take to dig 100 holes in 100 hours?",
    "answer": "20 men - each man digs 1 hole in 5 hours."
  },
  {
    "question": "5. What virtual digital currency, divided into 100 million units called satoshis, was created by developer Satoshi\nNakamoto in 2008?",
    "answer": "Bitcoin"
  },
  {
    "question": "6. In computing, ADSL stands for what?",
    "answer": "Asymmetric Digital Subscriber Line"
  },
  {
    "question": "1. What date has been set for the 2023 Zimbabwe elections?",
    "answer": "Wednesday 23 August 2023"
  },
  {
    "question": "2. Which member of the K-Pop band, ASTRO died on 19 April 2023? How old was he?",
    "answer": "Moon Bin, 25"
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Who were the finalists of the Champions League 2023?",
    "answer": "Manchester City and Inter Milan"
  },
  {
    "question": "4. Which bird is the International symbol for happiness?",
    "answer": "Bluebird"
  },
  {
    "question": "5. What color is the blood of an octopus?",
    "answer": "blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "6. Who is the new Nigerian President?",
    "answer": "Bola Ahmed Tinubu\n</|im_end|>"
  }
]